JULIE M. MERRITT

166 Main Street • Concord, MA 01742 Street • 339-235-4800 • julmerritt@yahoo.com

Sales & Channel Management Executive

An accomplished Sales Management Executive with experience in presenting and delivering solutions and services to the enterprise market. Results driven professional with extensive experience in areas of lead generation and sales management. Particularly in areas around cross selling with new offerings to build out new sales models.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LIVONGO CORPORATION, REMOTE EMPLOYEE

JANUARY 2019 - PRESENT

Livongo empowers people with Chronic Conditions to live happier and healthier lives.

Regional Sales Director, National Health Systems

- ✓ 100% Hunting role, everything from gathering emails to closing new logo contracts for a Whole Person Solution
- ✓ Sold into Self-Insured employers around areas of Behavioral Health, Diabetes, Diabetes Prevention, Hypertension, and Weight Management and closed 10 Health System new logos in 2019.

ELIZA CORPORATION, AN HMS COMPANY - DANVERS, MA

FEBRUARY 2017 - JANUARY 2019

Eliza runs programs that work with payors to engage people in their healthcare and drive results. Eliza works with health plans and employers to engage their population to use their healthcare services and improve outcomes.

Business Development Executive, New Logos

- ✓ 123% of 2018 \$1.2 Million Dollar New Logo goal, or \$1.482K Sold between 12 New Logos
- ✓ 100% Hunting role, everything from gathering emails to closing new logo contracts
- ✓ When Eliza was acquired by HMS I was picked to work on the sales integration team to build out cross selling into the HMS client base
- ✓ Weekly travel 200k miles flown domestically in 2018

TWINE HEALTH - CAMBRIDGE, MA (START-UP)

NOVEMBER 2015 - JANUARY 2017

A Health Activation Platform that increases patient engagement rates. It is software that health coaches and care navigators use to connect with their clients either face-to-face or on a virtual basis. There is a consumer app to increase engagement rates, improve care management, and analytics on outcomes.

DIRECTOR OF SALES, WELLNESS COMPANIES AND SELF-INSURED POPULATIONS

- ✓ 2016 was Twine's first sales year, so I found companies to sell to and generated my own leads.
- ✓ Used LinkedIn for lead generation and grew my connections from 6,000 to 22,000.
- ✓ Completed marketing activities such as blogging on LinkedIn and email and phone campaigns of targeted outreach to prospects to build a pipeline and close deals.
- ✓ I developed up a multi-million pipeline and got to Wellness and Population Health seniormosts in companies such as BCBS of Kansas, Crossover Health, Marathon Health, Onlife, and Walmart.
- ✓ Sold more than my counterparts.

VECNA TECHNOLOGIES - CAMBRIDGE, MA

APRIL 2014 - NOVEMBER 2015

Vecna is a healthcare IT company with solutions that provide a patient portal to hospitals.

DIRECTOR OF BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT

- ✓ Was 187% of goal against a 2015 \$1.5 million goal.
- ✓ Closed \$2.815 million in 2015: One licensing deal was \$2 million with PNC Bank, and there were 3 hospital deals of \$388k, \$325k, & 102k.
- ✓ \$2 million contract is a partnership deal. Worked on developing new software functions and planning the rollout into one of the partner's hospital chains of 85 hospitals.

Julie M. Merritt Page 2

✓ In charge of a \$2-million-dollar licensing partnership with the Advisory Board Company.

CARE CLOUD - BOSTON, MA (START-UP)

DECEMBER 2011 - MARCH 2014

CareCloud provides a cloud system for medical billing and electronic health records.

DIRECTOR OF CLIENT SOLUTIONS

- ✓ Started with CareCloud when they were 120+ employees.
- ✓ Directed sales and business development for medical practices in New England. Worked to build out the infrastructure of the sales team and how to generate leads in new territories.
- ✓ Competently carried a \$1M quota and completed product demonstrations over the phone and in-person. Was 115% of quota in 2012 and 105% of quota in 2013.

ATHENAHEALTH - WATERTOWN, MA

SEPTEMBER 2005 - DECEMBER 2011

Earned high-level promotions during 7 years with provider of leading edge cloud medical records company.

REGIONAL SALES MANAGER

JANUARY 2008 - NOVEMBER 2011

- ✓ One of five employees (out of 150) to qualify for all President's club trips in all 7 years with athena
- ✓ Developed the sales structure to secure new business and increase sales. Exceeded all sales goals, with team objectives ranging from \$5.5 million to \$7.5 million.
- ✓ Worked with channel partners and VARs to optimize lead generation and deal closings. Reviewed pipeline activity and forecasts daily. On-boarded and managed 30+ personnel in 4 years.
- ✓ Achieved 110% of goal in '11 with a 35% quota increase. Motivated sales team to a close rate of 26%; compared to 12% in other regions. The team ranked #1 in the cross-sell rate for complete athena product offering.
- ✓ Proficiently decreased sales cycles so 60% of deals closed in 30 days and 80% closed in 60 days. Worked on one channel partnership that lead to 40% of Athena's inbound leads.
- ✓ Selected to launch the company's first satellite office in Alpharetta, Georgia.

SALES EXECUTIVE

SEPTEMBER 2005 - JANUARY 2008

- ✓ Received the Rookie of the Year Award in '05. An integral role in transforming and expanding the sales division from a pilot program with five employees in '05 to a 45-employee operation.
- ✓ Efficiently surpassed all annual quotas; independently produced over \$1 million each year. Selected to pilot channel partner relationship with McKesson/PSS for lead generation development.
- ✓ Joined when Athena was 200+ employees and was poised for rapid growth and an IPO.

CORPORATE EXECUTIVE BOARD - WASHINGTON, DC

JUNE 2000 - AUGUST 2005

The company offers consulting services to corporations and is the sister company to the Advisory Board.

ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR, SALES AND MARKETING

JANUARY 2003 - JULY 2005

✓ Exceeded all annual quotas of \$1 million and made President's club each year. Closed deals with HR leaders at Fortune 500 companies, including Bank of Montreal, Fidelity Investments, Goldman Sachs, and Vanguard.

ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR, RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT

JUNE 2000 - DECEMBER 2002

 \checkmark Managed 150 clients to strengthen relationships and met 100% of annual goals.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ARTS - MAJOR IN ENGLISH, GEORGETOWN UNIVERSITY, WASHINGTON, DC (2000)

DIVISION I ROWER AND RESIDENT ASSISTANT

BOARDING SCHOOL IN SOUTHBOROUGH - MA, ST. MARK'S SCHOOL